hello everyone it's the active inference
textbook group welcome to everyone who's
joining
it is cohort twos meeting one on
september 2nd 2022
so welcome everybody
um
just to
mention
gather features and then let's just have
a few minutes to
say hello if we would like
um
on the bottom bar is where you can mute
yourself or turn off your video so
that's helpful for people
um
on the bottom bar also there's a smiley
face where you can
see a raised hand
and the hand raise
which you can also reach with just
hitting six
is how you have to
lower it manually but that's how we'll
know that people want to speak which is
like super helpful
um
and moving with the arrow keys but
everyone's figured out if they're here
the main asynchronous tool is going to
be the coda but first before we go
through the coda
um let's just take a few minutes and
anybody who wants to
can just
say hello if they want
i want to ask nail to make a few steps
from the entrance
to make it open
okay
neil oh thank you
all right nice
does anybody want to just say anything
anyone returning from
um the previous
cohort who would just want to say
anything
or
anything else before we launch into more
of like
the overview of the coda
someone can just speak up they don't
need to raise their hand ali and then
anyone else
hi i'm ali i'm an independent researcher
from iran
this is the second time
i'm joining the textbook
uh the previous cohort was fascinating
in my opinion and i hope to
meet a lot more people
on this cohort as well and
looking forward to another fascinating
journey together thanks
thank you ellie anyone else can raise
their hand or
give any thought
thank you i can say hi
i'm blue i'm also joining from
the first cohort and i will be um
helping
sometimes when daniel's not round
so it's nice to meet all of you guys and
i'm excited to get deeper into the
machine
all right awesome ragnar and then anyone
else who wants to raise their hand
yeah hey everyone
that's my first cohort but really
excited to be joining
um i'm currently like a data scientist
at the
at q bio it's a startup in san francisco
building like a digital
twin of the human body
but i've always been very fascinated by
the active by active influence also read
the new book
but excited to be joining the court and
meeting other people who are passionate
about the topic
awesome
yvonne and then anyone else who wants to
raise your hand
yeah hello
my name is ivan i'm
based in iran and in acting institute
i
direct a
another
education program and here
i'm in a student role
all right
um
well this is the second cohort and
there's some people who are
also
rather rejoining this first part of the
book
or and or
in cohort two
uh or in cohort one part two
and the meetings are following so if you
want to stick around or if you're in
both that's totally
cool i think we're
obviously just
learning by doing with even the
structuring
so
hopefully people can
start to think about active inference
and how it applies to our processes
and uh
iterate and improve even within
cohorts within these next several months
together
so
anyone can also write questions in the
chat which is the second um
[Music]
set of button next to the people
um
all right
the first part of this onboarding is
going to be
in the
main single source of truth which is
posted in the nearby chat
so this is the document to bookmark and
use and contribute to as well as any
other ways that you want to be
contributing um like
in the institute or just in your own
work it's all
good however you're being engaged and
this is like our shared information
environment
everyone should have edit access but
this is fine time to check
we're gonna go through some of the pages
and how they've
been used in the previous cohort it's
also
extremely
rearrangeable so we we wanna and and
people can make copies of things and
we'll go through some features and so on
and just talk about how we'll use these
different pages and everything and if
anybody like
from the previous cohort or
who has a question about something you
can just raise your hand or use the chat
and like
there's
it's just good to clarify things as we
go
so the first page the top page here is
an overview
of this textbook group
and you can right click and download the
textbook pdf itself it's an open source
textbook it's the march 2022 active
inference textbook
with par pizzulo and fristen
some people probably already completed
scanning it over or reading it deeply
others are
probably going to go download it
the directory page gives some
information about what these different
coda pages are
participation rules and guidelines
this is something to note and also
provide your feedback on
which is
the synchronous and asynchronous aspects
of this textbook group which is to say
what we discuss in
recorded
and or active institute synchronous
conversations
and what we put into our shared
knowledge repository
unless it's signaled otherwise can be
considered as having this creative
commons attribution status
which is citation open source with
attribution so just kind of keep that in
mind and as we
explore um learning and
design decentralized science together
it will be
important to have people's feedback
but just wanted to note that because
it's kind of an important aspect of
doing work and it helps structure what
kinds of contributions you want to be
making in this shared document where
truly all contributions and questions
are really important the most basic
most speculative which we'll talk about
but this is what the status of those
contributions are
and we're here as students and
individuals
who are learning and applying active
inference
especially
in the second
half of the book
and of course probably in all of our
thinking on active inference or even
day-to-day work we're very interested in
applying active inference
also this is a textbook group
that has a learning in a student
basis
but that's going to be happening in new
ways inside and outside the group and so
again something to kind of just consider
and
give feedback on
so engagement will look different
for different aspects
even
with planning we still may not know like
what the synchronous and asynchronous
availabilities are for
your engagement with a textbook and with
the group
all the meetings are recorded which
we'll talk about
but mainly it's going to be about your
asynchronous
engagement with the textbook itself and
some different practices around that
also
anything else that you see as part of
your
learning
journey here
could be contacting people who you're
connecting with participating in a
discord
getting involved in some other projects
or activities that we have
looking more at projects with other
participants so it it's not all just
about reading and and um
we'll try to unpack that
um
you all have access to this coda
document some pages are are a little bit
fixed
and the ones especially with tables are
there to be like expanded upon and we'll
get through that
we um
have two ongoing cohorts
so if
people would like in the cohort too
which is
how we are here
by your
name
um or let us know if you're not added we
might just need to sync something
you could note whether you've downloaded
the textbook
made time in your calendar
for these synchronous meetings if it
works or like making time to re-watch it
or just making time to be
paying attention to this area
and then if um you're
uh like wanting to share
some blogging or potentially to do some
writing
around your
work
and if you want to place a link to your
site and contact email so people can get
in touch with you
so you can click those check boxes
when you've done those steps if you want
to
so
you're on boarded you have the
downloaded textbook you're making time
to participate in different ways
what is actually going to be the
participation
there's many ways to
learn and people are coming from a lot
of different backgrounds
which is
part of what our
group is um
about oh sorry i just for the recording
like wasn't fully sharing my own screen
um
but here are the
learning practices that we've
just sketched and we can add more too
so when you feel like contributing
or paying attention to this
um
textbook group
here are some practices
that might be interesting
for you to check out and also comment on
or improve like what
are you doing when you're working with a
textbook and that's going to range from
peripheral reading and viewing
could be experiential
it could be
computational
um especially as we move into the second
half of the textbook where there's a lot
more like model building
so
there's also some
uh templates
which you can also in coda
um like copy out to your own space if
you'd like
and there's some templates that are
around tracking your practices
in terms of your allocation of time and
like
keeping different um
accounting of your engagement or your
commitment there's no
rubrics this can this is an aside
document that only you have
um other
um
things you can bring in there
uh but that's just to say you can use
some
practices and accounting
if you like
just how you see fit
um and then
the live meetings themselves
you can see
the live meetings from cohort one
because they also were under the same
[Music]
open sourced with attribution approach
and then here
after this meeting this will be a link
that is rewatchable
and future meetings will be recorded as
well
but you can also see some discussions
from earlier cohorts
so that's a lot of the
like logistics and onboarding
[Music]
we can
see it goes through november
that's the rough timing it's variable
time commitment
of different types
through
november
strongly influenced by like
what your availability is and what
you're
coming to
and where you want to go and all of that
what happens along the way
are there any like logistical
questions or advice or things that were
missed
all right um jessica and then anyone
else and then maybe like alex or
something can mention the overview
um yes it's gonna fail so i'm jessica
i'm also a returning um
student participant for the course um
and i guess i just wanted to add like um
something that was really
um really useful last time around was
engaging in the discord with the
different participants
and kind of like learning from each
other so also like the
live informal chats
and
you know and kind of
asking questions of each other in on
real time and to learn
so those were like really helpful uh in
addition to the ones you know asking the
questions in like you know
in the quota and and going over them
here but it was also like that extra
level of interaction that i really
enjoyed last time
so i just wanted to add that part
thank you
thanks jessica i added the discord link
in the chat if anybody is not in it okay
any other like just logistical comments
does anyone want to mention a practice
or
pattern
that was relevant or they did that they
didn't or didn't expect
before we look at the pages where a lot
of our shared
work for people who choose to engage in
the reading and writing this way
before we even jump into any of it it's
just anyone have an overview
comment
about a practice or a way that they felt
like they were learning a lot
for me the translation of the math into
english was like mind-blowing
um and actually like it wasn't so much
the translation as like how much i
learned in the process and how much i
learned about like what i wasn't really
understanding so um i think that that
that was a practice that was like super
instrumental to helping random material
yeah
and it's not dumb like not even close so
all right so in the next um you know 35
minutes there's three
big areas to look at that are all part
of the same function of us learning and
collaborating they're also distinct
though
there's going to be some tables
which are used as reference in coda
so in coda where you can edit at
is able to call
like various types of things it can
reference a page
at which point that becomes a link to
the page
or it can link like
what we'll explore in just a few seconds
it can link a term
like if you want to talk about
variational free energy
and then that on mouse over can be used
to look at a lot of things like um
[Music]
the definitions and a lot of other
aspects that we'll continue to have
built so what is it um that these kinds
of references are often too
first let's look at the tables and then
into the descriptions of the textbook
and then the way that the discourse is
range so it's not about like any
importance or precedence it's just
going through it in this order
um
the ontology is a project
that has been scaffolded at the
institute since the beginning
which is the development of term lists
as well as their translations into
multiple
um languages so here's like a public
face this link on the ontology page
this is a public-facing version where
you can see
definitions
and then also the translation
into these current languages so if
anyone
has a language also that they are not
seeing here that they're familiar with
that is
there's 74 core terms
and it can be an awesome contribution
these ontology terms
allow us to do a lot of things like
again encoder
referencing when we're using a term
specifically
which is going to facilitate
like cross-linking
as well as translation and a lot of
other aspects
um so we'll see how the ontology comes
into play in the in the sections above
that are more about the book but these
are kind of static tables for
semi-static tables that will be used in
a lot of other parts above
the live streams
are
a table of live streams
the live stream series itself is paper
driven
and so if you're curious about a given
topic like communication
you may find that there are several
live streams and relevant papers there
inactive inference research we have a
table of some citations and this is
work from some knowledge engineering
projects that are also
always in progress in an area for people
to be involved in
with ways of
aggregating resources
and
bringing their accessibility
into working documents like this
um
and then there's just a list that's
referenced elsewhere so those are kind
of the static tables which are just some
live streams that people may enjoy or
are often brought up to contextualize
other papers that we might mention
um
and then the ontology table
the ontology structures a lot of the
technical discussions in the active
inference
field
first the textbook and then the
discourse that we'll have more on the
textbook this section textbook
is
the textbook is open source
hey gsrp do you have a
question
hi no i just i just managed to connect
right now i'm not very familiar with the
interface
cool welcome thank you
um the textbook section itself
is going to contain many
um
[Music]
tables and the table is going to be of
the type that is described in the page
so you can peruse these but
they're used for multiple reasons first
it's all enabled because the textbook is
open source
what
the um
kind of aliquoting of the textbook into
these
formats
which is a lot of the work that was done
in the first iteration of the first part
for the first five chapters then we'll
do that for the second
having a field that's callable as like
equation 2.1 means that anywhere you can
just do at equation 2.1
and then okay okay that's what 2.1 looks
like
and so
these can also be tagged
and these are contributions that are
incredibly valuable for people to make
if they feel
moved to want to do these types of
contributions
so that like when people
type in a term
like bayesian
a bunch of equations that are relevant
come up
then um
blue maybe do you want to describe
um what these
descriptions are of the equations
if you're there
okay
these
descriptions of you or ali do you want
to describe
sorry i was muted and i'm driving um
okay okay
yeah
i can uh describe really quickly they
are um the descriptions are like
literally how
you would read the math equation so if
you like
are you know you read like y equals mx
plus b this is like you know the um
y-intercept is equal to the slope times
the x-intercept plus
the um or sorry the y-coordinate equals
the slope times the x-coordinate plus
the y or y-intercept right so it's like
literally how you would read
the equations in active inference using
like english words for the terms that
they represent
thank you blue and those terms because
they're referencing
terms in the active inference ontology
this is going to help contextualize the
equation it's not the whole story on
equations there's a ton of discourse
below
and then when we get to questions in our
discourse
you can ask open questions at reference
or are stimulated by seeing formulas so
as hopefully becomes
clear
all math backgrounds and preferences are
welcome and everybody should be able to
find uh
meaning
and
again for the people who feel like doing
these kinds of annotations
or work like for example jakub
who showed some derivations and it was
like
oh the first one goes to the second and
the first one goes to the third
but the second one doesn't go to the
third
okay
well that's a different understanding
even without the equation of
how all of these terms which are natural
everyday terms
are linked to the formalisms because
the formalisms are
infinite journey
with math and everything
so that's why we're always looking to
increase the accessibility of what is
being related
so that in the natural language use
and in the
settings where we're wanting to apply
active inference we can interact with
these things
grounded in the formalisms but using
regular ways of um
communicating it's worth it because the
equations are going to be
peppered in the book as well as
technical and difficult concepts or big
questions that aren't equations so the
difficulty is not purely
analytical
it's also just um
everybody will have areas they're like
familiar with and unfamiliar with
okay figures is very similar the figure
information on the figure and then the
image is posted
so that
figure 2.2 again it can always be
clicked
so especially as these tables gain
completeness
and also we can even copy the whole text
of the book
to github or to um
pages
so we can make and this is all on the
road of developing interfaces for
learning and applying active inference
boxes and tables again similar to
figures
it just has images and it allows you to
call
box 2.1 okay that was what box 2.1 was
code so this is going to come into play
especially for people who have this
background or would like to learn more
and also in the second
half of the book
which is about model building
and here we'll be developing i know ali
and brock and jakob
many people are interested in this kind
of notebook driven development
so again if somebody is familiar with
like git and notebook
development and hopefully there will be
many opportunities there
um in the chapters these are just uh
this is a filtered view by chapter of
the questions asked regarding that
chapter
if somebody wants to really focus on one
section
and also these are editable pages um or
comment or if they're not
where you can just add
just anything you want on the chapters
these are the sections of the book
there's ten chapters and there's three
appendices
chapters one through five constitute
like an epistemic learning component of
the of the book
and then chapters six through ten
are
about building models
and about applying
still perhaps more theoretical than some
would imagine applying to mean but
relative to the first five it begins to
get applied
so these are just
sections of the book
there are the equations in a way that
they're going to be referenceable in the
discourse same for the figures boxes and
tables and code is something that people
can be developing more
especially in the second part of the
book
all right now to the
discourse itself
and the collapsing in the coda can start
helping a lot
so
just to go over these pages
so a really important page especially
for the live meetings is the questions
so this questions page is going to be
all the questions that have been asked
however you can also go into cohort 2
questions
to develop your own cohort specific so
it's all referenceable like the
underlying questions are all retained so
if you don't want to like
have your priors updated by what
previous people have asked then
don't look
however if you want to
see
and even improve
the kinds of questions and
discourse
and the way that the live meetings work
is that
the
questions that are for that week's topic
we will look at like we'll go okay
chapter one we're discussing today
this one has the most up
votes
and then we'll just try to go
through that list
we're not going to address every
possible one to the possible most
possible especially written level of
detail
however before any time including after
it's been discussed one time people can
continue to come back and give thoughts
and discourse
one thing about the book structurally is
there aren't any
questions or
cases provided
so there's a large opportunity to
develop
really quality and interesting questions
from
the very very
basics
of
a chapter's gist or context or anything
to really just open-ended questions
where there isn't even an answer per se
just kind of people
can just work on some unsolvable problem
or solve a problem or something
just at the end of chapter one because
kind of why not
um
so we go through the interesting ones
and clicking on this
kind of an icon in a coded table will
open up that
where it's easier instead of having a
text box that just becomes out of
control this is like
allowing a lot of discussion
people are bringing in different
resources
we can ask questions about using terms
in the ontology
all these kinds of things again the
questions can be
um and also the questions can um
reference parts of the book so oh this
is about chapter one and figure 1.2
okay
so that is how we'll do the live
meetings
and so
adding as many questions
as you would like
is great
just truly if whether it's something you
think is very simple and you just want
to
add it as something that somebody could
be asked
or something that is like okay just
checking
what is the difference between this and
that
that's a great or it can be open-ended
or it can be anything that you're
asking
and then we'll just try to discuss them
and continue to develop the discourse
on them so that is because so just it's
worth spending a lot of time on because
the question structure the live meetings
which is just the tip of the iceberg
hopefully you would get a lot just from
one hour per week
of the discussions and seeing how people
have updated the coda
and their own notes
however
arguably you'll be developing a lot more
if you're also
asking questions and
writing them down to yourself or at
least adding some here so that's the
questions aspect
um ideas and insights don't have to be
framed as questions but people can just
add
anything that they were thinking or
reflecting on
[Music]
just
like different ideas and insights from
the book if they'd like
um then we have
several other aspects
so next is the math learning group which
was a great
um innovation by several the
participants here who are really active
so
they know who they are and they all like
helped
steward and template
a really
accessible and inclusive approach to
math discussions and
um
[Music]
this is an area for people on any
side of some perceived math
comprehension
situation they can be in this
group
and we'll set
sometimes amongst the people who want to
commit to a certain set of times
but it does it doesn't have to be
recorded it's
um
[Music]
it was not previously
and here are just several pages within
the math learning group which is really
everyone but that was kind of like the
joke
first there are several overviews
written
that are
there was one table update so here if
you see a strange sign these can be
fixed it's just like okay you just have
to replace it with that word but it was
a previous table is being referenced but
there's a few little cases like that
um
these
math overviews were
can be collaboratively improved to be
like so they introduced section
2.2 this equation because it's going to
show this just try to walk through some
of you have overviews of the book with
the technical eye
there are math learning resources
that are just describing some of the
resources people have found relevant for
learning a lot of the background
materials which have been named
differently in different um
settings and there's also a lot of
change even in the fundamentals of
active inference and free energy
principle recently
so
it's not like an
um
[Music]
absolute or total claim about what the
bases or backgrounds are that being said
certain areas like
linear algebra and stochastic processes
and statistics
can be
helpful
anyone else can add more of course but
i'm just mentioning a few areas and what
the appendices are
mentioning
notation
here
is connecting
some of the natural language ontology
terms
to the notation used
in discrete time active inference and
continuous time active inference
so that we can then
kind of keep some of the formalisms in
mind and get familiar with some of the
notation
as we're talking about affordances or
observations
because that is the
structure of
the relationship of the ontology
also not in its
final form
but at least there is a specific thing
here's some math learning questions so
it's just a separate section
for questions if people don't want to
put them in the main table but of course
math questions again of the most
confirmatory to the most difficult are
also welcome in the questions table but
these are some questions about
conversations to have
around
learning and approaching the math
and
there'll be some experimentation with um
math typewriting
um
okay
i'll um mention the other sections
before project ideas
resources so here's some resources that
people have found are as relevant also
searchable
here are some uh here's a feedback form
which we'll update later in the cohort
and a link for people who want to join a
future cohort
and then here's just
some
ideation
on what you would tell future
participants
different written feedback
different ideas people have had
about how to be involved in structuring
the textbook group differently and
better which
should and will happen
[Music]
in the coming cohorts
and then errata is uh just like some
random stuff random thoughts people have
and a few little typos or uncertainties
in the book
those kinds of
things
so just to kind of return to the
overview and then we can have the rest
of the time with any like discussions or
thoughts people are having
we are
finishing
our
onboarding
for this cohort 2
and then
we're going to take two
weeks per chapter and we're going to go
through the first five chapters
the chapters are not extremely extremely
long in terms of page
but
there will be paragraphs where they're
just
inscrutable or
like you could also think about them for
a long time
and so
that's where the practices come into
play
to whatever extent is possible
having at least read through if or or
listened if you prefer audio form
to the chapter
would be the best
before a session on that chapter
like ideally these are not motivating
you to then check out chapter one
it's the most helpful to have read the
section before
chapter one is
a very overview
so it will spur many questions and it's
non-technical and then all the equations
and so on start beginning in chapter two
um
so
try to paste things so that you are
prepared for the discussion at least
having
read or listened
to those pages
and just looked at what the figures were
and ideally also having contributed some
questions or and even some discourse on
the questions or thoughts on it so that
in the live meeting it's not like okay
here we've read the question
who has a thought on it it could be like
well here's two
perspectives people have shared
is there any other
thought on how that could happen
so well in chapter one which again is
very overview
styled
these will be pretty
open
discussions
about the context of active inference
maybe even ongoing changes in active
inference
one overall note is
this mod this textbook
there's of course many ways to think
about it but it's like describing the
kernel
of
a framework
which is the action perception loop
and some formalisms and approaches
towards formalisms for the action
perception loop
the papers
conferences literature at a very rapid
pace
is elaborating in a ton of directions
which actually i will leave to ali to
describe because i think
you'll have a lot to say all this
well yeah uh actually on resources page
uh i've accurate curated
a collection of 17
papers
uh and i've put them roughly in the
order of increasing technicalities
and
i think these papers might come in handy
as we go through the textbook because
i mean the textbook is
especially some chapters are really
dense and will definitely need some
additional resources
so
feel free to add any other
papers or articles articles you came
across or reorder them in any way
you see fit but yeah this is uh
this page might
[Music]
be useful uh
for some people if they want to
gain a little bit more deeper
understanding in terms of
the essential concepts and so on
thanks
yes jessica
um yeah i guess i wanted to build up on
at least um
comment because i found like there were
a lot of like the papers that he uh
suggested that were very helpful like
i'm a pretty much beginner and in this
space and also with a lot of the math
and and a lot of the papers that he
added and
which was sort of like straddling
between so like statistics and also um
what the book and is talking about
on
is it i think just i guess to like back
up a little bit like one of the
challenges that i found is like in the
textbook it's frame a lot of the
statistical material and some of the
math is framed
from the active inference obviously and
approach
and the link back to some of the basics
in statistics might be lost
and there were like some references that
i
suggested and mentioned that allowed me
to be able to
make the connections to understand like
okay so
inactive inference one is looking at
this term that's normally used in
statistic
in this other way this is how
you know
it connects and and be able to learn a
little bit of the foundation for that
and then be able to um
make the transition to how it's used in
an active inference and
framework or more than this approach and
so yeah so that's what i wanted to like
build up because they were like you know
very like useful on connection to kind
of go from more foundational
aspect to then connecting it to active
inference and how they are applied
in this sense
thank you jessica
um
[Music]
yeah i i
think it's
great that the math group opened up a
lot of that
discussion in space
because this is a textbook and to kind
of return to that idea of it being a
kernel
this is going to be focusing on
a
didactic
slash exemplar
single agent
case
one entity
involved in an action perception loop
and it's going to describe
that process
it also doesn't describe the um every
aspect from every possible perspective
it's a short book overall
and the step by step
which is probably linked in all these
the step-by-step guide
for example is also almost book length
you'll find other almost book length
approaches to learning
including ones that take very different
approaches
like the path that they take in a
step-by-step guide with even some of the
same authors is not the same as the
textbook
and the textbook structure is not
without
uncertainties and so on there's like
from the fundamental mathematical
to especially chapter five when the
neuroscience is going to get connected
broader discussions around systems and
complexity and cybernetics control
theory
philosophy and especially the
introduction
of the 4e etc embedded extended
things like nested communicating
cyber physical systems
are not
going to be in the middle of chapter two
except potentially by just mention
so
the research has a huge amount of these
cases
and like ramifications of active
inference
which often you'll see with an adjective
before like deep active inference now
it's considering something about
temporal depth or something
um
so again it's all say the textbook is a
lot
and yet there's more
especially in application
so that again just returns us to the
practices and thinking about this as
learning the kernel of active inference
or a kernel
or a
distilled representation by some of the
people who have been working in this
area
for a long time
like carl fristen and those who are
bringing
a sort of
computational
view
that and physics-based view
which is mainly explored
in
[Music]
recent literature but also not in the
textbook
anyone could have more thoughts on that
but
or just general thoughts on the
practices or
the
way to approach the textbook
even though published in march
or april this year
still
it feels like a lot has
changed
in inactive inference or what do people
think what is the way to approach the
textbook
ali and then anyone else
well uh just one thing that i think um
might be helpful to keep in mind is that
is that um
as uh if people want to go through the
the additional resources and
the other papers in the literature
uh well uh it would be helpful to keep
in mind that the notations used in the
book
is mostly different from most of the
notations used in the rest of the
literature so uh this might be confusing
at the initial stages so
um yeah that's one caveat
that i wanted to mention
thanks for mentioning it um it's one
reason why we have this
language ontology driven approach
because we'll be able to make columns
for different papers this is written
down elsewhere i just want to note that
for people who like do want to really
parse through a paper
where there is alignment
in what the papers are discussing
or or disagreement or ambiguity or all
the above
but is about the terms and the concepts
which is also what connects the
formalisms whether the math analytical
equation formalisms
or the computational
coding implementations
whatever formalisms are being used
when they're being discussed outside of
formalisms it's with
these kinds of terms
so decision making and policy selection
affordances capacities for action
and then that's represented a certain
way in equations
maybe as a bold letter or maybe as
a vector or there's just that is where
there's
heterogeneity
is the ways that
certain um
[Music]
terms are
represented because people are coming at
this for many threads which we'll be
learning about
but in um statistics maybe they're used
to talking about like y is a predictor
of x
but then in
bayesian models of perception and
cognition maybe o is used for
observation and s is for a hidden state
but
that might be an analogous situation
[Music]
in the
actual topics and how they're related
and
um
[Music]
yeah any other
thoughts on this
oh the last section which of here is the
project ideas
jessica or anyone
want to give an overview on the project
ideas
um yes um
i guess like in general the idea is
if you have on
a specific
way that you want to
practice like learning by doing on
active inference or like a project in
mind and
to share it and with the community to
see if there's all the other people who
are interested in
joining you and exploring it in that um
manner
and and so yeah so you share the idea um
you put in your name and so that other
people can contact you on and also tap
themselves on
saying that they're interested
and and then you know you can also like
organize yourself and to
create like a separate um
study group or like you know project
and group and to do this um together and
then there's already like some um
projects idea that already like emotion
and that you can also learn by doing so
like black friends and which is also
part like the
institute itself and it's a project but
then they're all the ones that are also
like more independent from all the
previous um
participants in the
you know study group on
yeah so it's very very informal and
just you know post a flag and
and see
you know what momentum generates and you
know what feedback you get out of it
yeah
thank you jessica yeah there's just
people can continue to add and it looks
like some people even are adding things
but it ranges from
audio recordings of the book
going into various aspects of the rigor
and accessibility of the textbook
uh actin foundations course
which i know brock and ali have
worked on and
other types of textbook enrichment
um people interested in domain specific
cases many of which
we can scaffold really well in active
block friends
all the meetings
this meeting is in gather so we can be a
little bit more like face to face also
potentially use
breakouts spatially but also be not
related to the discord if people don't
want to be that way it's not that it
always maybe we can
you know see how things evolve in
platforms but we're here so that we can
have a really focal
study
and connection time
and the project meetings are in our
discord
those or or they can be arranged as
people see fit but by default in the
discord like for active block for
instance for others
and that helps provide some visibility
for your project even if someone's not
in the textbook group
and um
[Music]
as the months go by hopefully people see
a lot of ways to
want to apply active inference the book
will make several
comments to that effect too
um
[Music]
does anyone have any other comments
otherwise we'll
end this first discussion
neil and then anyone else
yeah i mean this all looks absolutely
fantastic i was just wondering
what is it that acting
uh what's the objective
for the acting group what are you trying
to
get out of this and what might we
help
to achieve that
well appreciate that i hope we can
find out
and co-create how
but
in general our
mission at the institute is to address
education and research
so those are the two sections of the
textbook
and these types of groups and people's
engagement in them and the projects
and
other facilitations of the institute as
they see relevance
in a changing ecosystem they're all
helpful
um rowan
uh yes i just wanted it's a very simple
question
in regards to the questions for the
upcoming chapters
do we are we able to put those questions
in before the meeting is that is that
the aim so
as i'm reading the chapter and i've got
a question i can pop it in there and
then that'll be answered during the
session
yes
so you could just like click in which
chapter you want the question to be in
and then just hit enter
dot dot okay new question
dot dot and then
you can um
[Music]
add if you want in this field you can
use the at and say okay at
equation 2.1
and then the question could be like
i saw equation one dot dot but yes
adding them before
will make those discussions
really um
rich and
have some starting places for the
discussion and then if someone can't
make the discussion that's also fine
because then their questions will be
addressed
and yeah be given visibility so we can
continue to address it
okay
good thank you
all right any final comments
you